{"tossups": [{"question": "This program refurbished the Cominco plant as part of its P-9 Project, and it absorbed the similar British \u201cTube Alloys\u201d program under the direction of Leslie Groves. One of its facilities was built to take advantage of TVA hydroelectric dams at Oak Ridge, and it used a gun range at Alamogordo to carry out the July 16, 1945 Trinity test. For the point, name this program led by J. Robert Oppenheimer from Los Alamos National Labs, where the first nuclear weapons were produced.", "answer": "<b> Manhattan Project</b> (prompt on descriptions of the American nuclear weapons development program)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Philip Wigle and John Mitchell had their death sentences commuted for their roles in this event. The Mingo Creek Association was enraged by John Neville\u2019s change of heart regarding this event. General\u201cLight-horse Harry\u201d Lee gained fame for putting down this rebellion, the only time a sitting U.S. President led troops in the field. It stemmed from Alexander Hamilton\u2019s effort to repay the public debt from the Revolutionary War. An unpopular excise tax triggered, for the point, what Western Pennsylvania revolt over a distilled spirit?", "answer": "<b> Whiskey</b> Rebellion", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Public opinion on this event changed after the publication of Thomas Maule\u2019s Truth Held Forth and Maintained. One person in this event was accused of using the Malleus Maleficarum; that African slave, Tituba, was owned by Samuel Parris and had supposedly corrupted Abigail Williams. For the point, name these 1690 hearings in which 20 people were executed for supposedly working with Satan.", "answer": "<b> Salem Witch Trials</b> Page 1", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This country\u2019s last monarch was a member of the Barakzai dynasty. An interview in<em> Rolling Stone</em> caused Stanley McChrystal\u2019s removal from this nation. The Durrani Empire was centered in this modern country, where two large monuments were destroyed in the Bamiyan Valley in 2001 and where Operation Enduring Freedom helped install a government led by Hamid Karzai. For the point, name this country ruled from Kabul.", "answer": "<b> Afghanistan</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "John Balliol was replaced by a council of twelve after holding this position for only four years. The Darien Scheme perpetrated by holders of this title failed to create a colonial empire based in Panama. Idi Amin\u2019s fantastical claim to be the last one of these people was made into a 2006 film. After the death of King Elizabeth I, a holder of this title from the Stuart line gained control of the English monarchy. For the point, name this title, held by James VI, abolished by the Acts of Union of 1707 that subsumed its namesake country into Great Britain.", "answer": "<b> King</b> of<b> Scotland</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "During Operation Pastorius, 8 intelligence operatives infiltrated this country. The Lookout Air Raids caused numerous fires in this country, and one of this country\u2019s oil fields was bombarded by the I-17. This country names a bomber designed by the German Ministry of Aviation for long-range attacks, and six people died in this country after the explosion of a Fu-Go, a fire balloon, in 1945. For the point, name this country, whose Aleutian Islands were invaded during World War II.", "answer": "<b> United States</b> of America (or<b> US</b>A; accept<b> America</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Eduard Goldstucker\u2019s<em> Literarni noviny</em> periodical inflamed tensions before this event, and Klement Gottwald\u2019s broken promises were attacked in one speech delivered during this event. The power of the StB secret police was curbed as part of the Action Program, which was pronounced during this movement. Its leader attempted to implement \u201csocialism with a human face,\u201d but this liberalization effort was eventually overturned by Soviet force. Alexander Dubcek [doob-check] led, for the point, what 1968 Eastern European uprising centered on the capital of Czechoslovakia?", "answer": "<b> Prague Spring</b> Page 2", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A \u201cPriest King\u201d statue from this civilization\u2019s late period is missing both of its arms, and steatite seals of elephants and unicorns have been discovered at the civilization\u2019s two main cities. A \u201cdancing girl\u201dfiguring from this culture made of bronze is currently displayed in the Karachi Museum, and the first urban sanitation systems in the world were created by this civilization. The Aryan invasion hypothesis describes the end of this civilization around 1000 BC. For the point, name this Bronze Age civilization located by a namesake river in northern India and Pakistan.", "answer": "<b> Indus</b> River<b> Valley</b> civilization (accept<b> Harappa</b> and/or<b> Mohenjo-Daro</b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "Members of this country\u2019s military were absolved from prosecution by the Law of Due Obedience. This country experienced the Infamous Decade after the overthrow of Hipolito Yrigoyen. This country was ruled as a military dictatorship under Leopoldo Galtieri in the early 1980s. The children of the Mothers of the Plaza de Mayo \u201cdisappeared\u201d during the Dirty War in this country. For the point, name this country once ruled by Juan Peron from Buenos Aires.", "answer": "<b> Argentina</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In this event, Nicholas Hubbard and the playwright Pierre Beaumarchais were part of one side, while Francis Dana declined an offer to participate for the other. Lucien Haunteval requested that merchant claims be paid off by the American government in this event, and Jean-Conrad Hottinguer\u2019s demand for a 50,000 pound bribe to meet with Charles Talleyrand was met with the reply, \u201cNo, no, not a sixpence!\u201dThe Quasi-War resulted from, for the point, what Adams administration scandal involving Elbridge Gerry, Charles Pinckney, and three unnamed French diplomats?", "answer": "<b> XYZ</b> Affair", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This author wrote a collection of essays detailing \u201cLife in George W. Bush\u2019s America.\u201d One of this author\u2019s characters plays piano at the Holiday Inn in Midland City. That character, Bunny, and his father, Dwayne Hoover, appear in this man\u2019s novel<em> Breakfast of Champions</em>. This author wrote about a man who meets Eliot Rosewater while in a mental ward after surviving the firebombing of Dresden, which this author survived as well. For the point, Billy Pilgrim travels to the planet Tralfamadore after becoming \u201cunstuck in time\u201d in what American author\u2019s<em> Slaughterhouse Five</em>?", "answer": "Kurt<b> Vonnegut</b> Jr.", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Short Fiction"}, {"question": "This government created a \u201cFoundation for the Study of Human Problems\u201d that advocated the use of eugenics. A bicycle velodrome was used by this government during the Vel\u2019 d\u2019Hiv Roundup to house Jewish detainees. This successor government to the Third Republic, whose motto was \u201cWork, Family, Fatherland,\u201d was headed by the victorious commander at the Battle of Verdun. For the point, name this fascist French government led by Marshal Philippe Petain during World War II.", "answer": "<b> Vichy</b> France (or<b> Vichy</b> government)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man replaced Abel Upshur after the<em> USS Princeton</em> incident, and as James Monroe\u2019s Secretary of War, he created the Bureau of Indian Affairs. This man became the first U.S. vice president to resign after the Peggy Eaton affair soured his relationship with his former running mate. For the point, name this author of the South Carolina Exposition and Protest, a senator who advocated for nullification.", "answer": "John<b> Calhoun</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One of these events was led by Nils Dacke in Sweden against Gustav Vasa. Jack Cade led one of these events that looted London before being driven out by its citizens. One led by Guillaume Cale in Normandy was called the Jacquerie. John Ball encouraged one of these events that destroyed the Savoy Palace, eventually forcing Richard II to agree to abolish sefdom at Mile\u2019s End. Wat Tyler led, for the point, what sort of event, in which angry farmers revolted against the government?", "answer": "<b> peasant wars</b> (or<b> peasant revolts</b>, or anything indicating a<b> conflict</b> involving<b> peasants</b>; accept serfs in place of peasants before serf is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This city\u2019s first female mayor was Rosario Roble, and it is currently led by Miguel Mancera. An 8.0 magnitude earthquake struck this city in 1985, and as this city hosted the 1968 Summer Olympics, students were killed in this city\u2019s Square of the Three Cultures in the Tlatelolco Massacre. The Angel of Independence stands above a mausoleum honoring Miguel Hidalgo in this city\u2019s Paseo de la Reforma. For the point, name this North American city, the largest Spanish-speaking city in the world.", "answer": "<b> Mexico City</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This man defeated Muzio Clementi in a duel before Emperor Joseph II. He wrote out none of the cadenzas for a Clarinet Concerto written for Anton Stadler. A five-voice fugato that recapitulates all of the themes from the last movement ends his 41st symphony, while another work by this man, his Serenade No. 13, opens with a Mannheim rocket theme. For the point, name this Austrian composer of the<em> Jupiter</em> Symphony and the light \u201cEine Kleine Nachtmusik.\u201d", "answer": "Wolfgang Amadeus<b> Mozart</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Commerce flowing in and out of this body of water were subject to the Sound Dues, and the Skane market was an annual herring market on this body of water. The Victual Brothers pirated commerce in this body of water, with safe ports at Rostock and Straslund, as well as the island of Gotland. Kronstadt guarded the approach from this body of water to St. Petersburg, and it is connected to the North Sea by the Kiel Canal. The Hanseatic League dominated trade in, for the point, what body of water, bordered by Germany, Sweden, and Denmark?", "answer": "<b> Baltic</b> Sea", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "This man described himself as \u201cobnoxious, suspected, and unpopular\u201d in order to persuade Thomas Jefferson to write the Declaration of Independence. This man\u2019s<em> Thoughts on Government</em> was written in praise of mixed constitutions. As a lawyer, he claimed that \u201cFacts are stubborn things\u201d as he acquitted six British soldiers who participated in the Boston Massacre. This man signed the Alien and Sedition Acts to quell dissent during the Quasi-War. For the point, name this second President of the United States.", "answer": "<b> J</b>ohn<b> Adams</b> (prompt on Adams alone; do not accept John Quincy Adams)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The main divisions in this man\u2019s works were created by Aristarchus of Samothrace. This author\u2019s use of the phrase \u201cwine-dark sea\u201d has led some scholars to posit that the color blue was undefined during Antiquity. Lost works in this man\u2019s \u201cEpic Cycle\u201d include the Epigoni and the Nostoi, as well as a \u201cLittle\u201dversion of a work by this man that opens with the \u201cRage of Achilles\u201d. For the point, name this blind Greek bard of the Odyssey and the Iliad.", "answer": "<b> Homer</b>", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "The Barid was a postal service established during this empire, which suffered a Berber revolt under Hisham. This empire was founded in the aftermath of the First Fitna and was dissolved after Abdallah ibn Ali defeated Marwan II in the Battle of the Zab. Charles Martel defeated this empire at Tours. For the point, name this Islamic caliphate founded by Muawiyah, a dynasty led from Damascus that succeeded the Abbasids.", "answer": "<b> Umayyad</b> Caliphate", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "One of the first engagements in this conflict was the Battle of W\u00a8orth, which followed a brief advance towards Saarbr\u00a8ucken. The Chassepot rifle was unable to defeat steel Krupp artillery in this war, which saw Marshal Bazaine was besieged in Metz with the Army of the Rhine. Helmuth von Moltke the Younger surrounded the Army of Ch\u02c6alons during this war, ending the Second Empire at the Battle of Sedan. For the point, name this brief war, which saw the defeat of Napol\u00b4eon III by a country led by Otto von Bismarck.", "answer": "<b> Franco-Prussian War</b> Page 5", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Before it commemorated Princess Diana, a 1973 version of Elton John\u2019s song \u201cCandle in the Wind\u201dmourned the death of this figure. A publicity photograph from the film<em> Niagara</em> was used to create a diptych of this actress, and she sported a pink dress in a rendition of \u201cDiamonds Are a Girl\u2019s Best Friend.\u201dHer last completed film,<em> The Misfits</em>, was written by her ex-husband Arthur Miller.<em> The Seven Year Itch</em> and<em> Some Like It Hot</em> starred, for the point, what blonde actress who died in 1962 at age 36?", "answer": "Marilyn<b> Monroe</b> (accept Norma Jeane<b> Mortenson</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Film"}, {"question": "Judicial Watch was the first organization to bring attention to this set of documents. Bryan Pagliano was tasked with watching over these documents. A Romanian hacker nicknamed \u201cGuccifer\u201d hacked some of these documents sent by Sidney Blumenthal, and Richard Leon angrily denounced the State Department\u2019s speed in releasing these documents. The House Select Committee on Benghazi has been investigating, for the point, what set of communications sent by a former Secretary of State?", "answer": "<b> Hillary Clinton\u2019s emails</b> (accept either name; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "The 1928 San Felipe Segundo hurricane is also named for this lake, where it created storm surges that flooded Pahokee and Belle Glade and killed thousands. After that hurricane, a new dike named for Herbert Hoover was built around this lake, in which \u201cthe muck\u201d was once farmed. Its primary inflow is the Kissimmee River, and its sheet outflow into the Everglades was controlled in the 20th century by building canals to the Miami River. For the point, name this largest lake in Florida.", "answer": "Lake<b> Okeechobee</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "One work inspired by this event opens with a voice repeating \u201cmissing.\u201d A triple string quartet by Steve Reich commemorating this event opens with the first violin imitating a phone left off the hook. John Adams\u2019<em> On the Transmigration of Souls</em> memorializes this event with sound from the voice recorder of American Airlines Flight 11. A 1,776 foot tall building nicknamed \u201cFreedom Tower\u201d was built to remember and replace two towers that were destroyed during this event. For the point, name this 2001 terrorist attack.", "answer": "<b> September 11</b>th, 2001 terrorist attacks (or<b> 9/11</b>/01 attacks; accept equivalent descriptions)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This city\u2019s Yu Gardens were home to the Small Swords Society. Only foreigners were allowed in this city\u2019s Huangpu Park until 1928. Zhou Enlai purged hundreds of Communists in a 1927 massacre in this city. This city is the world\u2019s busiest container port city and is home to a waterfront district called the Bund, opposite the Oriental Pearl Tower. For the point, name this most populous Chinese city, which lies on the southern end of the mouth of the Yangtze River.", "answer": "<b> Shanghai</b> Page 6", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "During this time period, one man fell asleep while leading forces at the Battle of Klushino, leading to his defeat and death. A man named \u201cSidorka\u201d was the last of a group of three usurpers to the throne during this period, and Vasily Shuysky\u2019s ascension to the throne during this time resulted in the invasion of Sigismund III of Poland. The death of Fyodor I began this period, which was dominated by \u201cfalse Dmitris\u201d and ended by the ascension of Mikhail Romanov. For the point, name this period of turmoil in Russian history after the fall of the Rurik dynasty.", "answer": "<b> Time of Troubles</b> (do not accept or prompt on \u201cthe Troubles\u201d)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In the aftermath of this event, \u201cOklahoma houses\u201d were built in Moxham to shelter the homeless, and Andrew Carnegie built a library that now houses a museum dedicated to this event. This event, which the courts labeled an \u201cAct of God,\u201d was caused by a lack of maintenance by a Fishing and Hunting Club, of which Henry Clay Frick was a member. Over two thousand people died when this event struck the Conemaugh Valley. A failed dam caused, for the point, what 1889 catastrophe in Pennsylvania, the deadliest flood in American history?", "answer": "<b> Johnstown Flood</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Spectators of this event congregate on Henman Hill. This event was the final major in its sport to adopt equal pay for men and women. Over three days in 2010, Nicolas Mahut and John Isner played the longest match in history at this tournament, where, in 2013, Andy Murray broke a 77-year streak without a Men\u2019s Singles winner from the host country. For the point, name this tennis event played on grass courts at the All-England Club in London.", "answer": "The Championships,<b> Wimbledon</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "Former UAW President Leonard Woodcock was the first person to serve in the modern incarnation of this position. John Huntsman resigned this position during the Obama administration to run for the 2012 Presidential nomination. Prior to being Director of the CIA, George H.W. Bush served in this role unofficially, because this post didn\u2019t exist until January 1979, shortly after the U.S. ended its diplomatic recognition of Taiwan. Max Baucus currently holds, for the point, what American diplomatic post based in Beijing?", "answer": "U.S.<b> Ambassador</b> to the People\u2019s Republic of<b> China</b> Page 7", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "Francis Sands is a CIA operative during this conflict in Denis Johnson\u2019s novel<em> Tree of Smoke</em>. Walter Dean Myers\u2019<em> Fallen Angels</em>, set during this conflict, is often banned in schools for its gory depictions of this war. Ted Lavender is shot while returning from the bathroom in the title story of a collection set during this war written by Tim O\u2019Brien. For the point, name this war, the setting of<em> The Things they</em> <em>Carried</em>, which saw American soldiers attacked during the Tet Offensive.", "answer": "<b> Vietnam</b> War", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Short Fiction"}, {"question": "This civilization\u2019s writing system is displayed by the Cascajal [cas-ca-hall] Block found in Lomas de Tacamichapa. Matthew Stirling studied its sites at La Venta and Tres Zapotes. Art from this civilization shows \u201celongated men\u201d as well as 10 large monuments found at San Lorenzo in modern-day Veracruz. For the point, name this Mesoamerican civilization dating from 1500 to 400 BC, known for its construction of large stone heads.", "answer": "<b> Olmec</b> civilization", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This law was questioned by Bentley\u2019s paradox and re-applied in vector fields using surface integrals by Gauss. A test of this law used lead weights mounted on a torsion balance by Sir Henry Cavendish. This inverse-square law, the subject of a plagiarism dispute with Robert Hooke, relates a force to the product of two masses and the distance between them. Isaac Newton described, for the point, what law that describes how any pair of bodies are attracted to each other by a fundamental force?", "answer": "Newton\u2019s Law of<b> Universal Gravitation</b>", "metadata": "Science - Physics"}, {"question": "This country\u2019s only king served as Emir of Cyrenaica before uniting this country\u2019s three provinces; that king was overthrown in 1969 by members of the Free Officers Movement. That movement was led by the author of<em> The Green Book</em>, who led this country for 42 years before being killed near Sirte by members of the National Transitional Council. King Idris once ruled, for the point, what African country where Muammar Gaddafi ruled from Tripoli?", "answer": "<b> Libya</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The Princes in the Tower were allegedly killed by, for the point, what last Yorkist monarch of England who was defeated at the Battle of Bosworth Field?", "answer": "<b> Richard III</b> Page 8", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "One leader of this group wrote the essay collection<em> Soul On Ice</em>. Another member of this organization, Fred Hampton, was killed by Chicago Police as part of the FBI program COINTELPRO, which aimed to undermine it. This group used open-carry laws to patrol the streets with guns, and ran the Free Breakfast for Children program in its native Oakland. For the point, name this black nationalist group led by Huey Newton during its prominence in the 1960\u2019s and 70\u2019s.", "answer": "<b> Black Panther</b> Party (accept<b> BPP</b> or the<b> Black Panther</b> Party for Self-Defense)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This artist painted<em> Dido Building Carthage</em> and showed a legislative building on fire in<em> The Burning</em> <em>of the Houses of Lords and Commons</em>. This artist painted a misty seascape of a ship that fought during the Battle of Trafalgar being towed to its final berth, and depicted people drowning behind a<em> Slave Ship</em>. For the point, name this British artist of<em> The Fighting Temeraire</em>, who painted the \u201cGreat Western Railway\u201d in<em> Rain, Steam, and Speed</em>.", "answer": "Joseph Mallord William<b> Turner</b> (accept JMW<b> Turner</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This leader unretired after John Crosbie announced an unpopular gas tax and Joe Clark\u2019s government dissolved. He refused to take cover after protesters threw bottles at him during the Saint-Jean-Baptiste Day Riots, and he responded \u201cJust watch me\u201d to the question of how far he would go to solve the kidnapping of Pierre Laporte by the FLQ during the October Crisis. For the point, name this 1970s Liberal Prime Minister of Canada whose son, Justin, became Canada\u2019s Prime Minister in 2015.", "answer": "Pierre<b> Trudeau</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "William Mason and Charles Richards designed this company\u2019s Model P. The founder of this company names a historic district in Hartford, Connecticut which contains his manor, Armsmear. After being fired from this company, Rollin White was hired by its competitor, Smith & Wesson. \u201cThe Gun that Won the West\u201d was a .45 caliber revolver produced by, for the point, what gun manufacturer named after its founder, Samuel?", "answer": "<b> Colt</b>\u2019s (Patent Firearms) Manufacturing Company", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This author\u2019s defense of David Hume in a letter written to his friend, William Strahan, was attacked for supposedly endorsing Hume\u2019s atheism. This man argued for a system of universal education until age 10 in one work, and in one of his works, he argued for a comprehensive system of morality based on the concept of an \u201cimpartial spectator\u201d within. This author of<em> The Theory of Moral Sentiments</em> noted that division of labor could increase productivity in industries such as pin-making. For the point, name this Scottish economist, most famous for his treatise<em> The Wealth of Nations</em>.", "answer": "Adam<b> Smith</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "In one role, this man has a bus door slammed in his face as his credit appears on screen. He directed a film in which a meddlesome dog is strangled by Lars Thorwald, who is later repeatedly blinded by the protagonist\u2019s camera flashbulbs. The original ending of one of his films features the Golden Gate Bridge being covered by the title creatures. In another film by this director, Eva Marie Saint and Cary Grant are chased across Mount Rushmore. For the point, name this \u201cMaster of Suspense,\u201d the director of<em> Vertigo</em>, <em>The Birds</em>, and<em> North by Northwest</em>.", "answer": "Sir Alfred Joseph<b> Hitchcock</b> Page 9", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Film"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A rebel group in this country was founded by Fred Rwigyema [we-jay-mah], who was killed on the second day of a civil war in this country. Paul Kagame took over that group, the RPF, which ended a ceasefire after this country\u2019s president, Juvenal Habyarimana, was shot down above Kigali Airport. For the point, name this central African country where hundreds of thousands of Tutsis were killed in a 1994 genocide.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Rwanda</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A private Institute of Sex Research set up in this city during the 1920s coined the term \u201ctranssexual\u201d. The play \u201cI Am a Camera\u201d was adapted from Christopher Isherwood\u2019s novel \u201cGoodbye to\u201d this city, and was later made into the movie<em> Cabaret</em>. Berthold Brecht premiered his<em> Threepenny</em> Opera in this city, and many artistic endeavors in this city were later stopped by Ernst Rohm and the SA. For the point, name this bohemian center of the Weimar [VYE-mar] Republic during the 1920s, the capital of modern-day Germany.", "answer": "<b> Berlin</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s first two disciples made golden caskets in order to preserve the hairs given to them by this man, who later preached at a Deer Park. The \u201csangha\u201d refers to a group of people who follow this man\u2019s teachings, and relics of this man are known as \u201csarira.\u201d This figure\u2019s mother, the Queen Maya, dreamed of a white elephant before his birth, and he was kept from death, sickness, and poverty as a youth. This man\u2019s religion gained popularity for its opposition to the caste system in India. For the point, name this founder of an religion that promotes the Four Noble Truths.", "answer": "The<b> Buddha</b> (or<b> Siddhartha Gautama</b>, either name)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "In one of this composer\u2019s works, a title character allows himself to be wounded by Melot. In \u201cArt and Revolution,\u201d this man introduced the idea of the \u201ctotal work of art.\u201d One of his operas ends with the \u201cLiebstod\u201d and opens with a namesake harmonically-ambigous chord. This author of \u201cJewishness in Music\u201d wrote<em> The Mastersinger of Nuremberg</em>, later used at Nazi rallies. For the point, name this German composer of<em> Tristan and Isolde</em> and the<em> Ring of the Nibelung</em> cycle.", "answer": "Richard<b> Wagner</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "During this election, an accusation of one side\u2019s party platform requiring \u201csome sort of Gestapo\u201d to implement was received poorly by the public. The campaign promise \u201cLet us face the future\u201d was used by the winning side in this election, which saw Archibald Sinclair, the Liberal Party leader, lose his seat. The winning candidate in this election promised to create a universal National Health Service and replaced a man who had delivered the \u201cblood, toil, tears, and sweat speech\u201d. For the point, name this first post-war election in the UK, which saw Winston Churchill\u2019s Conservatives lose to Clement Attlee.", "answer": "<b> United Kingdom</b> general election of<b> 1945</b> (accept<b> UK</b>,<b> British</b>,<b> English</b> election of<b> 1945</b>; accept<b> 1945</b> alone after \u201cUK\u201d is mentioned) Page 11", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Frederick Muhlenberg was stabbed for supporting this agreement in the House, and effigies of this treaty\u2019s namesake were burned across the East Coast. The St. Croix River was set as a boundary in this agreement, and although the British retreated from their Western forts, it failed to stop impressment of American soldiers. For the point, name this 1794 treaty between the United States and Great Britain, negotiated by the first Supreme Court Chief Justice.", "answer": "<b> Jay</b>\u2019s Treaty", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Many of this event\u2019s ideas were ratified with the Benedictus Deus. The Tridentine Creed was created in the aftermath of this council, which commissioned the Roman Catechism and produced an Index of Prohibited Books. The sale of indulgences was reaffirmed by this council, which responded to the burning of a copy of the bull<em> Exsurge Domine</em> [ex-oor-gay doh-mee-nay]. Pope Paul III convened, for the point, what church council that responded to Martin Luther\u2019s Protestant Reformation?", "answer": "Council of<b> Trent</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This actress plays a character who is nearly abducted by Fingermen shortly before the Old Bailey is destroyed by a terrorist wearing a Guy Fawkes mask. This actress, who played Anne Boleyn in 2008, will play Jackie Kennedy in an upcoming film. For the point, name this actress who played Queen Amidala in the<em> Star Wars</em> prequel trilogy and won an Oscar for her role in<em> Black Swan</em>.", "answer": "Natalie<b> Portman</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This ruler founded the city of Antinopolis after the death of his Greek lover. This leader converted grain collectors known as Frumentarii into a secret police force. His forces defeated a rebellion started by Lucius Quietus, the Bar Kokhba revolt, and he ordered the construction of a fortification at the River Tyne to prevent barbarian invasions. For the point, name this Roman emperor, the successor of Trajan, who built a namesake wall in Britannia.", "answer": "<b> Hadrian</b> or Publius Aelius<b> Hadrian</b>us Augustus Page 12", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This artist painted a line of blindfolded soldiers in the aftermath of a mustard gas attack in<em> Gassed</em>. He painted an American president resting his hand on a stair railing in his<em> Portrait of Theodore Roosevelt</em>. This painter of<em> El Jaleo</em> [ha-lay-oh] caused controversy with his depiction of Virginie Gautreau wearing a revealing black dress. For the point, name this American painter of the<em> Portrait of Madame X</em>.", "answer": "John Singer<b> Sargent</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "Arthur Scargill led a coal strike against this politician, and faced a conflict against Leopoldo Galtieri. This politician\u2019s opposition to give children a third of a pint of milk per day led to the nickname, \u201cMilk Snatcher.\u201d This leader resigned from one position after instituting a poll tax known as the Community Charge, was targeted by the Brighton Hotel bombing, and won the Falklands War. For the point, name this \u201cIron Lady,\u201d the first female Prime Minister of Britain.", "answer": "Margaret<b> Thatcher</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This event was described as a \u201cjourney for peace\u201d in an announcement televised on NBC. Winston Lord was cropped out of photographs of this event. Henry Kissinger participated in this event, which began with a handshake with Zhou Enlai and included an hour-long conversation with Mao Zedong. For the point, name this 1972 event, the first time a sitting U.S. President visited a country with capital Beijing.", "answer": "Richard<b> Nixon\u2019s visit to China</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The Earl of Dunmore built a 14-meter-high stone cupola in the shape of this food in Scotland. The Ginaca machine peeled and cored this fruit, whose crowns can be replanted. In 1900, a plantation and cannery were built by James Dole, cousin of Sanford Dole, the President of Hawaii. For the point, name this tropical fruit named for its resemblance to the cones of a conifer tree.", "answer": "<b> pineapple</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {}, {"question": "The production of this commodity by indebted laborers in Samut Sakhon was investigated in 2015 by the Associated Press. In 2014, Charoen Pokphand Foods, the world\u2019s largest farmer of this food, was found by<em> The Guardian</em> to purchase feed from fishing boats manned by unpaid laborers. For the point, name this seafood that has been peeled by slaves in Thailand.", "answer": "<b> shrimp</b> (or<b> prawn</b>s)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}